You'll learn to love her. Warts and all.
Nanny McPhee is a fantasy, comedy, family film directed by Kirk Jones.
Widower Cedric Brown hires Nanny McPhee to care for his seven
rambunctious children, who have chased away all previous nannies.
Taunted by Simon and his siblings, Nanny McPhee uses
mystical powers to instill discipline.
And when the children's great-aunt and benefactor, Lady Adelaide Stitch, threatens to
separate the kids, the family pulls together under the guidance of Nanny McPhee.
Nanny McPhee, played by Emma Thompson.
Mr. Brown, played by Colin Firth.
Evangeline, played by Kelly Macdonald.
Simon, played by Thomas Brodie-Sangster.
Tora, played by Eliza Bennett.
Lily, played by Jennifer Rae Daykin.
Nanny McPhee is a 2005 comedy drama fantasy film directed by Kirk Jones,
based on the Nurse Matilda character by Christianna Brand.
Set in Victorian England in the 1860s, it stars Emma Thompson (who wrote the screenplay) as Nanny McPhee, along with Colin Firth,
Kelly Macdonald, Derek Jacobi, Celia Imrie, Patrick Barlow, Imelda Staunton, Thomas Sangster and Angela Lansbury.
It was co-produced by StudioCanal, Metro-Goldwyn-Mayer Pictures, Working Title Films, Three Strange Angels, and Nanny
McPhee Productions with music by Patrick Doyle, and produced by Lindsay Doran, Tim Bevan and Eric Fellner.
It was released theatrically on 28 October 2005 in the UK by United International
Pictures and on 27 January 2006 in the US by Universal Pictures.
Thompson also scripted the film, which is adapted from
Christianna Brand's Nurse Matilda books.
The filming location was Penn House Estate in Buckinghamshire.
A sequel, Nanny McPhee and the Big Bang, was released in 2010.
The film explores themes of loss of loved one, nanny,
education, family relationships, widower.
The tone is lighthearted.